She broke the rules... and changed their lives.
Dangerous Minds is a drama film directed by John N. Smith.
Former Marine Louanne Johnson lands a gig teaching in a pilot program for bright
but underachieving teens at a notorious inner-city high school.
After having a terrible first day, she decides she
must throw decorum to the wind.
When Johnson returns to the classroom, she does so armed with a no-nonsense attitude informed by her military
training and a fearless determination to better the lives of her students -- no matter what the cost.
Louanne Johnson, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Hal Griffith, played by George Dzundza.
Mr. George Grandey, played by Courtney B. Vance.
Mrs. Carla Nichols, played by Robin Bartlett.
Mary Benton, played by Beatrice Winde.
Waiter, played by John Neville.
Dangerous Minds is a 1995 American drama film directed by John N.
Smith, written by Ronald Bass, and produced by
Don Simpson and Jerry Bruckheimer.
It is based on the 1992 autobiography My Posse Don't Do Homework by retired U.S.
Marine LouAnne Johnson, who in 1989 took up a teaching position at Carlmont High School in Belmont, California, where most of her
students were African-American and Latino teenagers from East Palo Alto, a racially segregated and economically deprived city.
Michelle Pfeiffer stars as Johnson.
Critical reviews were mixed, with some critics praising Pfeiffer's performance but
criticizing the screenplay as contrived and full of stereotypes.
The film grossed $179.5 million and spawned a short-lived television series.
The film explores themes of high school, california,
rap music, karate, naval officer.
The tone is emotional.